♪〜
〜♪
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
拝啓 お父さん お母さん
Dear Mom, Dad...
... big big sister, middle big
sister, little big sister...
大姉(おおねえ)ちゃん 中姉(ちゅうねえ)ちゃん
小姉(しょうねえ)ちゃん
... big big brother, middle big
brother, little big brother...
大兄(おおにい)ちゃん 中兄(ちゅうにい)ちゃん
小兄(しょうにい)ちゃん
... Dougie, Anry, Rodney,
Mikey, and little Sandra.
ダグちゃん アンリちゃん
ロドニーちゃん
マイクちゃん サンドラちゃん
How are you?
I'm doing fine.
お元気ですか？ 私は元気です
（ミリィ）
うわあ… おはようございます
Good morning.
（メリル･ストライフ）
ミリィ  また手紙を書いてて
完徹しましたわね
Milly, you were up all night
writing home again, weren't you?
えー エヘヘ
That's what happens when you insist on
writing to each little niece and nephew.
ご丁寧に おいっ子 めいっ子
ひとりひとりにまで書くんだから
Ta-dah! I'm getting rave
reviews as The Milly Monthly!
ジャン！ 今じゃもう
月刊ミリィちゃんとして—
大好評なんですよ
Quality aside, you write
as much as an author.
枚数だけなら 作家並みですわね
Don't you write home, ma'am?
先輩は書かないんですか？
えっ
I did at first,
but not any more.
最初は書きましたけど
今はさっぱり…
But that's normal.
でも それが普通ですわよ
それに—
Besides, what would they say if I
told them I was with Vash the Stampede?
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードと
一緒にいるなんて書いたら—
何て言われるか…
So you don't
want to write them?
書きたくないんですか？
It's not that
I don't want to...
そ… そういうわけじゃ
...I know I should, but it
always seems like such a hassle.
書くのが面倒くさい… じゃ
逃げなんですけどね
（銃声）
（メリル）あっ
（２人）ええっ　ハッ！
（人々のどよめき）
Oh, hey, sorry about that,
my hand slipped.
（バドウィック）悪(わり)い悪(わり)い
手が滑っちまったよ 手が
（爺(じい)さん）よくもまあ
いけしゃあしゃあと この悪党が！
You have a lot of nerve,
you impudent scoundrel!
（婆(ばあ)さん）こんな脅しに
誰が乗るもんですか！
We're not dumb enough
to be scared off by you!
I see. It's all
very clear to me now.
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
なーるほど よーく分かった
There is merit
to your words...
確かに立派な言い分だが—
...so stand forward with your
heads held high and say them!
そういうのは前に出て
胸を張って言おう！
We won't give up our land!
手放しませんわよ あの土地は！
Yeah! You can go back
and tell that to Morgan!
そのとおり
帰ってモーガンに伝えるがええわ
Did you hear me,
you old fogies?!
聞いているのか？ ご老体！
Oh, please! My gun
only went off by mistake.
ヤーダな
今のは誤射ですよ  誤射
（爺さん）何が誤射だ
このクチビルゴーレムめが！
Mistake my boot,
you fat-lipped golem!
What?
（バドウィック）なに？
Fat-lipped golem?!
クチビルゴーレムだ？
That's so funny my trigger is
about to twitch with laughter!
笑うね
トリガーもカタカタいうぜ！
（２人）ダメー！
DON'T!
（ヴァッシュ）ほげええー！
（発砲音）
（バドウィック）うわっ ああっ！
That is so dangerous!
危ないですわよ 全く！
If you make this
broom-head angry...
このほうき頭を
キレさせたら—
...you'll have more than injuries
and property damage to worry about!
ケガや器物破損程度じゃ
きかないんですわよ
マジで！
Good grief!
（バドウィック）…って
危ねえのはどっちだよ！
Your back-smashing tag team
is much more dangerous than him!!
後からラリアット
食らわしたりして！
（壁が崩れる音）
（バドウィック）あああ！
（バドウィックの叫び声）
It's a small sacrifice
in a great clause, ma'am.
大事(だいじ)の前のふすまです 先輩！
Okay, never mind!
Way to go, Milly!
オーケー ドンマイ
レッツゴー ミリィ
And that's it?
（ヴァッシュ）それでいいのか？
Bodyguards?
（メリル）用心棒？
Exactly! We would feel so much
safer if you two were to guard us.
そうじゃ　あんたたちが
いてくれれば心強いんだが
I'm sorry, but company regulations
forbid us from taking part-time jobs.
も… 申し訳ないんですけど—
社則でアルバイトは
禁止されてるんです
I see...
How about you then?
そうか…
じゃあ 君やってみんか？
Why are you asking him?!
なんでそうなるの！
It was the way he moved when he
shielded us! I know he's extraordinary!
わしら かばってくれた
あの体さばき！
ただ者じゃないと見た
Am I? Well, I try!
そう？ 苦しゅうないっすよ
アハハハハハッ！
Out of the question!
ダメダメ！
Do you have any idea
who this broom-head is?!
あなたは このほうき頭が何者か
分かってるん…
Then will you take the job?
なら引き受けてもらえるかね？
（メリル）あああ…
わあー！ 困ってる人のために
一肌脱ぐなんて—
Wow! Only you would think
of using your position...
...to help out
people in need, ma'am!
さすが先輩ですね
し… しかたありませんわ
W-We have no choice.
It fits the category of
Risk Prevention like a glove.
リスク回避という業務の一環にも
バッチリ合いますし…
（メリル）なんで あなたまで
ついてくるんですの？
Why are you coming with us?
アハハハッ…
少し気になることがあってさ
Oh, something was
bothering me, that's all.
Keep out of this
one, understand?
（メリル）今回の件は
手出し無用ですわよ
Yes, ma'am.
（ヴァッシュ）はいはい
That is our land.
（爺さん）
あそこが うちの土地じゃ
（メリル）ああ…
This is incredible...
（メリル）すごーい
It's nowhere near
a ship, so how?!
シップの近くでもないのに
どうして…
It's just like a geo plant!
まるでジオプラントみたいですね
（ヴァッシュ）いや ここは
ジオプラントそのものさ
No, this is a geo plant.
（爺さん）おそらく地脈を伝って
影響が飛び地したんだろうな
We think that a geo plant ran along
a mineral vein to form this offshoot.
The land value has skyrocketed so high,
it's worth 300 yarz of ship!
土地も べらぼうに上がって
船の周囲の300ヤーズ並さ
でも それだけじゃ
ここまでならない
Maybe, but it wouldn't have
gotten this far on its own.
It would have taken
incredible effort.
並大抵の努力じゃ無理だ
20 years ago,
it was only a tiny bud.
確かに20年前は小さな芽じゃった
But I couldn't believe my eyes.
それでも我が目をうたぐったさ
To think we could raise
this land on a planet like this...
こんな星の中で
この土地が育っていく
You have no idea
how that kept us going.
それにどれだけ
我々が支えられてきたか
That's right!
Our lives and hopes are here!
そう
ここには
わしらの人生と希望がある
But what does that have to
do with hiring bodyguards?
でも それと用心棒を雇うことと
何の関係が？
You saw what happened earlier.
さっきの件を見たじゃろ？
The landowner, Morgan, has
threatened us time and time again...
地主のモーガンは
この土地の権利書をよこせと—
...trying to force us
to hand over the deed.
繰り返し
いやがらせを続けてきおる
But that will end tomorrow.
だが それも あしたまで
Once we get this deed over
to City Hall, he'll be stumped.
この権利書を役所に届ければ
手出しできん
（男Ａ）おーい
そろそろ交代の時間だ！
Hey! It's about time
to change shifts!
（男Ｂ）うー 寒(さみ)い寒(さみ)い
It's freezing out there!
It gets cold at night!
（男Ｃ）夜は冷えるな まったく
I really appreciate this.
悪いね いつも
Hey, don't sweat it!
なーに いいってことよ
This place has always
been our playground!
この場所は昔から
俺らの遊び場だったんだ
They can't have it!
なくしてたまるかってんだ！
And besides, we have two
gorgeous girls with us tonight!
それに今夜は—
べっぴんのねえちゃんが
２人もいるしなあ
（男Ｄ）
朝が来てほしくねえくれえさ
I almost wish morning
would never come!
（男たち）ハハハハハッ
That reminds me,
where is Broom Boy?
そういや ほうきのにいちゃんは？
I made him go
back to town.
町に戻ってもらいましたわ
ここにいたら同じことですから
There's no reason
for him to be here.
What's this, a fight
with the boyfriend?
なになに？ 彼氏？ ケンカ？
ゲホ ゲホ ゲホ
He is not my boyfriend!
違いますわよ
（ミリィ）イヒヒヒヒヒ
What are you laughing at?!
何 笑ってますの？
We're going to
do the rounds now.
私たちも見回りに行きますわよ
Coming!
（ミリィ）はーい
（メリル）あっ！
うーっ！ 寒いですね
It sure is cold!
What's wrong?
どうしたんですか？
Nothing, only I'm sure I've seen
the face in that picture before...
いえ 部屋にあった肖像画に
見覚えのある顔が—
描かれていたような
気がするんですけど
...but I can't quite place it.
- Oh! Like a passing fancy?
- A passing LI KENESS.
“他人のもつ煮”ってやつですか？
そりゃ“そら似”
No, but I'm sure I've
seen that face before...
いや… でも確かに見た顔なのよね
Who goes there?!
（２人）何者！
（バドウィック）
ま… 待て！ 撃つな！
Wait! Don't shoot!
You're that man!
あなた 昼間の！
This is a surprise...
You're those two girls!
驚いたなあ
あんときのねえちゃんたちか
You can see I'm unarmed.
Put your guns away.
見てのとおり丸腰だ
そっちも しまってくれ
What are you doing here?!
いったい何しに？
I came to talk some sense into Dad.
Morgan means business this time.
（バドウィック）
親父(おやじ)を説得しようと思ってよ
モーガンは今度こそ本気だ
Dad?
親父って…
You're the one
in the picture!
あーっ あなたは！
（バドウィック）フフッ
Yeah, I'm the unworthy son.
不肖の息子ってわけだ
So, Dad's inside?
親父は中だな？
Why did you point a gun
at your parents?!
どうして両親に
銃を向けたりしたんですか！
えっ
That's got nothing to do with you.
They wouldn't listen to reason!
関係ねえだろ！
ありゃ 聞き分けのねえ
親父が悪いんだ
I had to, or they'd
never get the hint!
ああでもしなきゃ
脅しにもならねえ
（ミリィ）この！
（バドウィック）おお！
You...
...fat-lipped jerk!
（ミリィ）クチビル野郎
（バドウィック）何すんだ！
What're you doing?!
- You'll pay!
- Stop it!
（ミリィ）許さ…
（バドウィック）この野郎！
Milly?!
（メリル）ミリィ！
（ミリィ）この！
Milly!
You ingrate! Bad son!
Stupid! Good-for-nothing!!
この罰当たり　親不孝者
バカ　ろくでなし！
な… 何だお前？
What's your problem?
（扉が開く音）
（爺さん）どうした？
What's all the commotion?
Who's fighting?
ケンカは…
Badwick!
バドウィック！
What do you think you're doing?
（モーガン）
いったい何をしているのですか？
あなたたちは
I came to see if you had taken
care of things, and what do I find?
もう片づいたと思って
様子を見に来れば…
Uh, Badwick wanted
just one more chance...
（悪党Ａ）あっ… あの
バドウィックのやつが—
もう一度だけ両親を
説得してみるって言うもんで
...to persuade
his parents, so we...
その…
（モーガン）うーん…
（悪党たち）あ…
He did, did he?
（モーガン）そうですか
I hired him for his diligence,
but he'll never be of any use to me.
よく働くので飼っておきましたが
やはり小者ですね
Not if he can't even
kill his parents.
親殺しもできないようなら
もう要りません
（衝撃音）
（モーガン）ん？
（悪党たち）なっ… 何だ？
What?!
（悪党Ｂ）えっ！
（パトリシアの叫び声）
（パトリシア）痛いわあ
That hurts!
くううううっ
Could I persuade you to
make a little less noise?
も… もう少し
穏やかに頼みたいですね
Excuse me?!
Like, loosen up!
（マリリン）なにー！
ケチくせえこと言いっこなし
You probably did something crooked
to get that car anyway!
どうせ あこぎなマネして
買ったもんでしょ？
いい？ こっちは親父と弟の
保釈金が懸ってるんだからね
Listen, my father's and my little
brother's bail money is riding on this.
If you try to take it out of our pay,
you're as good as squished!
代引きなんてしたら
即 握りつぶされると思いな！
も… もちろん
肉親を大切に思う気持ちは—
O-Of course! I can appreciate
the value of family!
よーく分かりますよ
（悪党たちのあきれた声）
よーし 私たちの鋼(はがね)の結束力
見せたげようじゃないのさ！
Great!
We'll show you the strength of
our steel-plated family bonds!
だあー！
All the way!
（マリリン）徹底的にね！
（バドウィック）
どうしても 言うとおりにする
つもりはねえのか？
So you're not going to
listen to me, no matter what?
権利書は渡さん！
We will not give him the deed!
こんな ちっぽけな自警団じゃ
役に立たねえぞ！
Your little band of vigilantes isn't
going to save you! He'll kill you all!
皆殺しだ！
モーガンは宝物を欲しがる
子どもと同じじゃ
Morgan is like a child
wanting a priceless treasure!
そんな なまやさしい覚悟では
土地も すぐ枯らしてしまう
In his idle care, this land
would quickly dry up and die!
バドウィック
Badwick...
...this land is a living thing.
土地は生きてるんじゃよ
（バドウィック）
けっ！ 命より土地が大切かよ
You think land is more important
than your own life?
You're probably happy to keep
sacrificing everything for this land...
あんたは そうやって土地のために
すべてを犠牲にして—
さぞや満足だろうよ！
チクショウ！
...damn you!
Max was right to die rather
than be raised by parents like you!
こんな親なら—
マックスも途中で死んで
正解ってもんだ！
（２人）えっ？
（大砲の襲撃音）
（爺さん･婆さん）ああっ！
- What was that?!
- An attack?!
（男Ａ）何だ！
（男Ｄ）敵襲か！
（男たち）うわっ！
（カンタ）ナハハハハハッ！
（カンタ）はっ！
（男Ａ）あ？
He ran away.
（男Ｄ）逃げた
うーん ナイスよ 母さん！
Smooth, Mom! Let's place
the next shot 5 yarz that way!
今度 もう５ヤーズ向こうで
決めてみましょうか！
き… 木には
当てないでいただきたい
Please do not hit the trees!
Do you understand?!
分かってますね？
Jeez, you're ruining my fun.
…んもう しらけちゃうなあ
Do you know who
you're talking to?!
私たちを誰だと思ってるのー？
We are Patricia,
Tonkichi, Chinpei...
パトリシア！
トンキチ！
チンペイ！
...and the one heading home is Kanta!
帰還中なのがカンタ！
All together...
つまり…
...we are Marilyn Nebraska
and Friends!
ネブラスカマリリンと
その仲間たちよ！
（パトリシアの雄たけび）
（マリリン）オホホホホホッ！
（パトリシアの話し声）
What? " You haven't done anything,
so don't hog the limelight"?
え？ 何もしてないくせに
目立ちすぎだって？
Oh, Mom!
You're so funny!
ヤッダな！ 母さーん
固いこと言いっこなしよ
Don't be such
a stick-in-the-mud!
Hey, they look like
they're enjoying this.
おいおい  ずいぶんと
楽しそうじゃねえか
Come on, Mom! Next,
let's give Chinpei a whirl!
さあ 母さん
今度はチンペイでいってみよう！
（パトリシア）はいー！
（マリリン）狙って 狙ってえ
Ready, aim...
せーの！
...and fire!
（パトリシア）ぐわーん！
（悪党たち）ひゃっほう！
They're here!!
き… 来たぞー！
We're under attack!!
敵襲だ！ 敵襲だあ！
That can't be!
It isn't time yet!
（バドウィック）バカな！
早すぎじゃねえか！ まだ俺が…
I'm still here!
Let's go, ma'am!
行きましょう 先輩！
R-Right! But...
えっ ええ　でも…
（爆発音）
（バドウィック）ヘッ だろうよ
It figures.
（メリルとミリィ）えっ？
Anyone would save
their own necks.
誰だって命は惜しい
That may be so...
（爺さん）そうかもしれん
Mom... Dad!
（バドウィック）
親父… おふくろ！
You can run if you want.
You don't have to die with us!
逃げてもいいぞ
お前まで死ぬことはない！
What are you talking about?!
（バドウィック）
なっ… 何言ってんだよ！
（男Ｃ）うわあー！
These guys are serious!
This is completely nuts!
やつら本気か？
めちゃくちゃだぜ おい！
（パトリシアの足音と雄たけび）
（モーガン）ヘヘヘヘヘ
（銃声）
（男Ａ）弾(たま)を持ってこーい！
Bring more bullets!
This is a real mess!
What should we do, ma'am?
えらいことになってますね
どうします？ 先輩
Ma'am?
先輩！
（爆風音）
Damn! We can't stop them!
クッソ  もうダメだ
I'm sorry about all this.
Thank you, you can go now.
すまなかった　ありがとう
もういいよ
Dammit, I'm so sorry...
（男Ｃ）チクショウ おっちゃん…
It's all right.
もういいんだ
Do we have an understanding?
（モーガン）
ご理解いただけましたかな？
Yes, now I understand how much
of a scoundrel you are!
ああ 貴様の
ろくでもなさ加減ならな！
お… 親父！
Dad?!
Don't worry.
Morgan won't shoot him.
大丈夫さ
モーガンは撃てやしないよ
The land will never
be his without the deed.
権利書がなきゃ 土地は
あいつの物にならないからね
それにしたって無茶すぎる
なぜ？
Dad is still pushing his luck!
Why is he doing that?!
You are such an idiot.
バカだね お前は
He's doing it to save me,
the land, and you, of course!
私と土地 そしてあんたを
守るために決まってるだろ
えっ？
I don't know
what you thought...
何と比べてんのか知らないけど—
...but that's how
much he loves you.
お前は その程度にゃ
愛されてんだよ
な… 何をいまさら
It's a little late for this
family-togetherness crap now.
調子いいこと言ってやがんだ！
This land does nothing but
eat money! It has no merit.
この土地を持っていたところで
金がかさむばかり
メリットなぞ 何もないでしょう
But here, look! Here's
something with more substance!
そこで ほら
はるかに現実的な代物です
I'll fill in the amount right now.
How many zeros would you like on it?
額面は今から
入れることにしましょう
好きな金額を言って…
（銃声）
（モーガン）ん？
そいつが答えだ  うせろ！
That's my answer.
Beat it!
So you want
to hasten death, do you?
（モーガン）なるほど 死に急ぐか
Very well, I'll accommodate you!
だったら
手伝ってやろうじゃないか
What should I do?!
（メリル）どうしたらいいの…
The moment you
kill me, you lose!
わしを殺した時点でお前の負けだ！
Don't you see all
of these witnesses?
証人は これだけ
そろっておるんだぞ！
フフッ… フハハハハハ
Witnesses? You must be joking.
証人？ 冗談だろ
一人だって残さんよ
I won't leave one of you standing.
I'm going to kill you to the last man.
パーフェクトに皆殺しにしてやるさ
（２人）えっ？
You can't!!
（ミリィ）ダメー！
（ミリィの荒い息）
ミリィ！
Milly!
ひ… 人の物とったら
ダメだって—
Didn't your father ever tell you not to
take things that don't belong to you?!
お… お父さんに
言われなかったんですか！
Miss!
お嬢さん！
Oho! What a tough
little helper you have!
ホッホー
頼もしい助っとですなあ
Be quiet, you!
うーるさーい！
Milly!
（メリル）ミリィ…
Oh, well. You were all destined
to become corpses anyway.
（モーガン）
まあ どっちにせよ あなたたちは
死体になる運命ですがね
（ミリィの震えた声）
（モーガン）
フッ！ いいかげん飽きてきました
そろそろ終わりと…
I've become tired of this.
Let's get this over with.
（メリル）そうはならないですわ！
I don't think so!
Now that I've heard your gruesome
plans, I can't let you off lightly.
物騒な話を聞いた以上
手加減は できませんわね
Make the slightest twitch,
and I'll be all over you.
ピクリとでも動いた順に
確実にいきますわよ
せ… せんぱーい
Ma'am!
From now on, think a little
longer before you act, Milly.
今度は もう少し考えて
行動することを勧めましてよ
ミリィ
Yes, ma'am.
（ミリィ）はい…
（婆さん）バドウィック
Badwick?
Badwick!
（扉を開ける音）
（婆さん）バドウィック！
Freeze!
（メリル）動かないで！
You people, why did it
turn out like this?!
全く どうしてこんなことに
なってしまうの！
If you had taken the money and sold
the land, there would be no damages!
お金をもらって土地を売れば
被害は出ない
No one would have to die!
誰一人 死ぬこともないのに
Freeze, I said!!
動かないでって！
But listen, Milly...
You were not wrong.
でもミリィ
あなたは間違っていませんわ
Your ability to display pure anger
when someone threatens his parents...
親に銃を向けたことに
まっすぐ怒れる気持ち—
...is very important.
大事なことよ
（モーガン）
ウハハッ 何だ それは？
What are those?
Do you really believe you can turn
the tide with those tiny derringers?
その ちっぽけな
デリンジャーで—
形勢を変えられるとでも
いうのですか？
Do you want to find out?!
試してみますこと？
That is, if you have the guts
to take on such huge odds!
デカいオッズを
受けて立つ度胸がおありならね！
（モーガン）なっ はあ…
ほれ！
Go on.
（パトリシア）ああああー！
なに！
What?
Hey, Morgan!
モーガンさんよ
I've got what you
want right here!!
あんたの欲しがってた物は
ここにあるぜ！
バドウィック！
Badwick!
おおー！ よくやりました…
Well done!
（バイクが走り去る音）
（メリルたち）ああ？
Get him!
やってしまいなさい！
（パトリシア）うぬぬぬああー！
ぬあああー！
（メリル）ダメ…
No!
I'll never make it!!
間に合わない！
But I have to try!
でも！
（チンペイ）うああ！
（パトリシア）もうー！
（モーガン）ああ…
That was amazing, ma'am!
（ミリィ）す… すごい先輩！
I did it?
なして？
フーッ！
That makes us even for
your help in the sand steamer.
サンドスチームの借りは返したぜ
Hey, is that all
the time I get?!
…って これだけ？ 出番！
So! So what did
you think of that?
ど… どどどうだー！
Don't say she didn't warn you!
No one can escape Meryl's derringers!
警告は したはずよ！
先輩のデリンジャーからは—
何人(なんぴと)たりとも
逃げられはしないのさ！
Next, she'll pinpoint
your hearts and brains!
次は脳も心臓もピンポイントよ！
You're through!
よろしく！
バカな！
偶然だ 偶然に決まってる
Absurd. It was nothing
but a lucky shot!
That gun is too tiny to do...
あんな銃で
そんなマネができると… ん？
...this much damage.
思ってる
No!!
（マリリン）イヤーン
How can this be?!
We're all washed up!
なんてことなの おしまいだわ！
Our super-cool technique
was supposed to be invincible!
私たちの超美技が敗れるなんてえ
S-Stop that cowardly blithering!
な… 何 ふぬけたこと
言ってるんですか！
That advance payment I made to you
wasn't cheap, so get your act together!
安くはない
前金取ってるんですから—
もう少し
しっかりしてもらわないと！
（パトリシア）うえーん！
（パトリシアの泣き声）
（モーガン）ぐあああっ
It's all right.
Dry your tears, Mother...
大丈夫よ
涙を拭いて 母さん
I'm sure Chinpei
is all right.
チンペイは きっと無事よ
（悪党Ｃ）早く 助けに行けよ
So go help him...
...or if your son means that much
to you, don't throw him around!
…っていうか そもそも
そんな大事な息子 投げるなよ
（パトリシアの泣き声）
（モーガン）なー もっと…
Get off!
I can't take any more
of this. Let's beat it.
（悪党Ａ）
俺 もう やんなってきたよ
帰ろうぜ
Yeah.
（悪党Ｃ）…だな
（爺さん）ハア…
Now, dear...
おじいさん
I think I overdid it.
ちょっと無理しすぎたわ
Right, love?
なあ？ ばあさん
Yes, I know. No matter
what may come of it...
分かってますよ
どんな結果が出ても
あの子が選んだ道です
...it's what he chose to do.
Let's see what he does.
あとは任せましょ
I can't find the words
to thank you both.
君たちには感謝の言葉もないよ
Especially you, Miss Meryl.
時にメリルさん
This is coming from an old man
who raised an idiot son...
あんな愚息を育ててしまった
私が言うのもなんだが—
...but everyone feels differently.
How you feel about your parents...
人の思いは それぞれだ
親子のあいだの感情も
比べられるもんじゃないだろう
...can't be compared with
how others feel about theirs.
Instead of feeling burdened, do
something more simple and important.
それを重荷に思うより—
もっと大切で簡単なことがある
Don't worry. Walk your own path
with your head held high.
悩むことはない
自分の道をしっかりと
胸を張って歩きなさい
Your life is their life. The very
fact that you are who you are...
命は つながっている
あんたがあんたでいることが—
...enables the people you love
to live through you.
愛すべき人を
生かすことでもあるんだよ
I don't know what's so great
about this stupid deed...
（バドウィック）
権利書だか何だか知らねえが…
（バドウィック）うっ くう…
（市役所職員）権利書ですね？
This is the deed?
Yeah.
It's in your hands now.
（バドウィック）ああ
じゃっ よろしく
Hey, just a moment!
（市役所職員）ああっ！
ちょっと待ってください
（バドウィック）うん？
There's one more claim
transfer in the envelope.
もう１枚 権利譲渡書面が
入っていますね
この受取人の所にある
バドウィックって—
Are you Badwick,
the beneficiary as written here?
あなたのことですか？
（バドウィック）はい！
Yes... That's me.
俺のことです
（ミリィ）どひゃー！
Yikes!
Ma'am, we're never
going to make it!!
先輩  間に合いませんよー
ごめんなさい ミリィ
I'm sorry, Milly!
It's my fault for
staying up all night!
私が夜更かししたせいで
（黒猫の鳴き声）
Ma'am! What are you doing?!
（ミリィ）
先輩 何してるんですか！
Mr. Vash's bus will leave without us!!
ヴァッシュさんが乗ったバス
出ちゃいますよー！
あっ はいはいはーい
I'm coming!!
♪〜
〜♪
People judge people.
（ヴァッシュ）人が人を裁く
おのれの理屈だけで
人の命が断ち切られていく
Lives are cut short because
of someone's personal logic.
Mothers, fathers, friends...
...entire pasts instantly vanish.
母も父も友も 過去のすべてが
一瞬にして虚空に消える
But should this take place
at the whim of one individual?
それを個人の感情だけで行うのは
果たして正しいのか？
A beautiful woman stood before
the corpses ofThe Roderick Thieves.
盗賊ロードレックの死体を前に
美しき女は言った
She told me that she had merely
cleaned up some useless garbage.
“何の役にも立たないクズどもを
大掃除しただけだ”と
Dominique the Cyclops told me
that this was spring-cleaning.
ドミニク･ザ･サイクロプスが言った
“これは大掃除なのだ”と